<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Economics on  </title>
      <generator uri="https://hugo.spf13.com">Hugo</generator>
    <link>http://thinkingco.de/categories/economics/index.xml/</link>
    
    
    
    <updated>Wed, 03 Oct 2012 02:33:24 &#43;0000</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>The extreme need of money Refactoring</title>
      <link>http://thinkingco.de/blog/the-extreme-need-of-money-refactoring/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2012 02:33:24 &#43;0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thinkingco.de/blog/the-extreme-need-of-money-refactoring/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time is Money&lt;/strong&gt; is a sentence which has become a symbol of our capitalistic society.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This highly condensed capitalistic bible brings in its meaning that whoever owns money owns time, owns our time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll let it sink down slowly: if time is money whoever owns money owns our time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is extremely true from small things to big ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you own money you can spend it instead of time or you can buy other&amp;rsquo;s time to do what you want (two faces of the same coin).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now think about taxation. In every modern state a portion of what you earn (in Italy about a half of it!) must be given back to the State.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This actually means that a portion of your job time is being worked for someone which is neither you nor your customer but the State. So a portion of your time is forcefully owned by the State through taxation, that is to say through money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is more than true for big financial players who literally own entire communities through their &amp;#8220;public debt&amp;#8221;. A clear example of this ownership is what has recently happened to Italy (just to name one of the european states that are actually bankers&amp;rsquo; driven).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Italy had a government democratically chosen (at least to the extent to which Italy is still a democracy), bad or good it was our choice (actually not mine because I choose not to vote).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was not the right government according to Big Finance and was to be replaced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On order was sent to sell italian debt from major banks to all their big customers, spread went madly up and main stream information told that Italy had lost the trust from markets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government went under (further) pressure and selected Mario Monti (trilateral, bildenberg and Goldman Sachs man) to build a technical government. In his government stands the banker Corrado Passera.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is just and example of how money and money makers own communities and can bring to power people they like and people who will serve their interest and not those of the communities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mario Monti (as Mario Draghi in the BCE and Papadopulous in Greece) are there for one and only reason: to force communities to pay their states&amp;rsquo; public debt to banks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So now the circle comes to its end:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;our states create public debt &amp;#8220;for our needs&amp;#8221; borrowing money from private banks in exchange for a compound interest rate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;during time the compound interest becomes the biggest part of states&amp;rsquo; debt so&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;states put higher taxes on the people owning more and more of their time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;states &amp;#8230;. create public debt to pay interests on their debt!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the usurers loop in which we are actually in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our freedom and our time is almost completely in the hand of money makers: private banks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is not good life code! Life is designed to be free and real, financial debt is enslaving and fake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was well known both in the Jewish and Christian worlds in both of which it was solved by &lt;strong&gt;debt cancellation&lt;/strong&gt;: each seven or twenty five years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was still well known that after some time debts will destroy real life and economy, the solution was simple and effective: &lt;strong&gt;systematically destroy debts&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In our terminal capitalistic society the solution is simply to destroy life and real economy (see what&amp;rsquo;s happening to Greece).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How can we refactor this code so that it can be useful to life instead of destroying it?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>