<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Mes on  </title>
      <generator uri="https://hugo.spf13.com">Hugo</generator>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/me/index.xml/</link>
    
    
    
    <updated>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Life</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/me/my-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/me/my-life/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My name is Tommaso and I live in Rome, Italy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m married with my wonderful wife Chiara we have a gorgeous baby named Giovanni and a new one coming in September 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are catholics and fond of Tolkien, Chesterton, Belloc and Lewis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a place in which I will primarily share my technological &amp;ldquo;EUREKAS&amp;rdquo; but I will also occasionally share ideas on different topics all centered on reflections about facts, thoughts and ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll strive to ground these reflections on some the following principles:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Love for life&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Catholic antropology&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Truth&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first point is very well mirrored in my technological choices. I program in Ruby and use the great Rails framework!
I challenge you to program in .NET or Java and keep your love for life! ;)
I&amp;rsquo;m approaching the Go programming language mainly because of the wonderful Docker project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dealing about the other two points I think that the biggest problem of the Catholic Church today is its exit from what are nowadays considered “separate fields” like: science, medicine, politics.
From a broader perspective the problem ultimately lies in the illuministic divorce between reason and faith. A deified reason doesn&amp;rsquo;t stand any other pretender to its throne.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the divorced reason has led us to where we are today: the biggest anthropological, ethical, economical and political crisis since the rise of democracy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today the role of the Catholic Church is the same: rise this civilization from its death.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To do this we need to &amp;ldquo;prove all things; hold fast to which is good&amp;rdquo; because &amp;ldquo;Whether Paul, or Apollos, or Cephas, or the world, or life, or death, or things present, or things to come; all are yours; And ye are Christ&amp;rsquo;s; and Christ is God&amp;rsquo;s&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With this in mind we need to bring back the lively union between reason and faith and hold the good things that reason showed us transforming all the terrible deviations that its divorce from faith brought about.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Job</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/me/my-job/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/me/my-job/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;IT Freelance since 2001.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been mainly working for two companies in the last years: the largest IT Training network in Italy PCSNET Srl and the biggest privately owned road safety focused company in Italy AISICO Srl.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For both I&amp;rsquo;ve:
- planned, implemented and deployed the IT infrastructure
- planned, developed and deployed the websites
- engineered out business processes into business web applications
- built web application sold to several customers and actually in production&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a Devop I use Linux virtualization in its Docker form.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;most complex dockerized network configuration&lt;/strong&gt; consists of a rack with 5 1U servers hosting:
- a fault tolerant haproxy
- an owncloud backed by GlusterFS distributed replicated volume configuration
- a PostgreSQL 9.3 + Postgis 2.1 database hot standby replicated
- three highly available wordpress websites
- a gitlab code repository&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;most complex business application&lt;/strong&gt; is a 12-factor rails 4 application used internally for guardrail crash test data collection and graphs and drawings production.
The rails 4 app is structured as a series of excel like auto updating forms. Drawings and graphs are made with SVG and d3.js.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The web application I developed for AISICO Srl is in production in ASTRAL Spa and Provincia di Latina and it is a web based road cadastre management system. It is 12 factorized and deployed through docker.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>